Doga Ege Ozden

Full-Stack Web Developer

North York, Toronto, ON • <u>dogaegeozden@gmail.com</u> • (+1) 647-784-8693 • <u>dogaege.pythonanywhere.com</u> • <u>linkedin.com/in/doga-ege-ozden</u> • <u>github.com/dogaegeozden</u>

Summary

Has a freelancer experience as a web developer. Founded the tamrinotte.pythonanywhere.com. Completed a Graphic and Web Design course in Seneca College. Proficient in time management, problem solving, internet basics, networking, client-side development, server-side development, MVC, Agile, SQL, No SQL databases, system and server administration on Linux operating systems and, Cyber security. Multilingual with fluent English and, fluent Turkish

Technical Skills

Programming Languages: C/C++, Python, JavaScript, Kotlin, Bash, Powershell

Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, Django, Express, WordPress, HubSpot, React-Native, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Linode, Apache, NGINX, Linux, Windows, macOS, Figma, Canva, Qt, Material UI, Git, Adobe Premiere Pro

Other Skills: Full-Stack Web Development, Software Development, Machine Learning, Distributed Computing, Data Structures and Algorithms

Work Experience

Package Handler at **UPS**

Nov 2021 - Present

Toronto, Ontario

- Built walls from packages, locked the layers to prevent accidents
- Sorted the packages in to correct trailers

Freelance Web Developer at The Art Collaboration

Aug 2020 - Sep 2020

Toronto, Ontario

- Developed a web application with a forum, calendar, online payment and a log in log out system
- Designed a page layout and presented the design specifications to the owner of the company

Education

Seneca College, Greater Toronto Area, ON

Business Administration and Marketing

May 2019 - Sep 2021

GPA: 2.9 / 4.0

- Excellent in inbound marketing including creating valuable content and user experience
- Understood the internet basics and learned web and graphic design
- Completed a project on web development using HubSpot, WordPress, HTML5 and, CSS3

Volunteer Experience

Digital Marketing Specialist at Keci Koyu

Jan 2021 - Feb 2021

Izmir, Ege

- Created advertisements on Google, using Google Ads and Google Analytics
- Solved the technical issues that, the company was facing with, by showing the company's correct location on the google maps using Google My Business. Led customers to find the store and, make purchases
- Optimized the web page for search engines using Google Trends and HTML5

Leadership, Awards & Extra-Curricular Activities

 Won the "Mimic Pro Digital Marketing Simulation Competition", a 10 week competition among students requiring keyword research, data analysis, writing content, SEO, email marketing, creating landing pages wireframes and, running A/B ad tests

Projects & Ventures

- Developed the <u>dogaege.pythonanywhere.com</u> a mobile responsive online portfolio using Django framework and solved the language barrier problem with the google translate's API
- Started his own video game company and promoted his games on tamrinotte.pythonanywhere.com
- Developed a mobile game called Magic 8 Ball using Kotlin programming language and Android Studio. And, sold it at <u>play.google.com/store/apps/dev?</u> id=5106309994896081965&hl=en&gl=US
- Finished the server-side development course on Mozilla Developer and deployed a local library web page online at radiant-brushlands-11667.herokuapp.com
- Created a web page to place his links using WordPress <u>dogaegeozden.wordpress.com</u>